Shreyas Vedpathak

▶ https://shreyasvedpathak.github.io ≧ https://stackoverflow.com/users/15226638/shreyas-vedpathak

PROFILE

A software engineering graduate with 1+ years of internship experience in software development in computer vision, backend development, cloud, and research & development. I seek to utilise my broad educational background and excellent analytical, technical, and programming skills to thrive as an entrylevel software engineer.

EDUCATION

MIT World Peace University

Jul 2018 – Jun 2022 | India Bachelor of Technology

Major: Computer Science

CGPA: 9.52

Sir Parashurambhau College

Jul 2016 – May 2018 | India

HSC

Branch: Science Percentage: 81%

SKILLS

Python • C++ • Docker • SQL • HTML • CSS • MongoDB • Scikit Learn • OpenCV • PyTorch AWS (Amazon Web Services) • Tensorflow • JavaScript • Flask • Perl • Bash • Shell

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Role: Software Development Engineer Intern

Nov 2021 – present | India

Company: Upiao Agrotech

- Created a Python package that would generate a numerical report and improved server response time by 45 percent.
- Contributed to the research team by brainstorming and authoring 2 patents.
- Restructured the server architect to make it scalable, flexible, and accelerated development with Docker and Kubernetes.

Role: Mentor Aug 2021 – present | USA

Company: DeepLearning.AI □

- Mentored candidates enrolled in specific Coursera courses by solving their doubts, sharing learning material, and career advice.
- Test new lab exercises before they are released to enrolled students.

Role: Data Analyst Intern

Mar 2021 – Jun 2021 | India

Company: Analytics Domain 🛮

- · Created a web application-based analysis tool that would leverage data from public APIs and web
- Curated 2 courses for Machine Learning and Deep Learning topics at the beginner and intermediate levels.
- With the produced courses and a variety of user-side UI features, developed a web app-based Learning Management System.

PUBLICATIONS

Genomics, High Performance Computing and Machine

Jun 2021

UIJRT (United International Journal for Research & Technology)

Learning Algorithms □

Bioscience Biotechnology Research Communications

PATENTS

A method and system for Encoding and Decoding data on objects by using geometrical shaped markers.

Jan 2022 | India

Patent Pending

A strong alternative to QR codes, barcodes, and RFIDs for simultaneously tagging, tracking, and recognizing multiple objects using computer vision techniques.

AWARDS

1st Runner Up - NTT DATA AI Hackathon 🗷

29 Jul 2022

NTT DATA

Ideate and build a working AI product to solve a healthcare-related problem. Won prize worth 1.25 Lakh.

Best Paper Award

Nov 2020

International Conference on Intelligent Systems, Data Science and Computing

Best Research Paper Award in Machine Learning Track.

PROJECTS

AutiScan 🛮

Nov 2021 – present

Final Year Project

- The candidate's reaction to a reference video is recorded, and their facial landmarks are utilized to classify them using a CNN + RNN deep learning model.
- Increased accuracy from 60% to 90% using finetuning.

Segmentation of Fire and Smoke in Nano-Satellite Imagery using Mask R-CNN and Res-UNet

May 2021 - Sep 2021

Research Project

- Separated natural objects such as clouds, snow, and rivers against smoke caused by a forest fire using Image Segmentation.
- Achieved 0.925 and 0.45 IoU scores using Instance Segmentation and Semantic Segmentation respectively.

Loan Management System - Flask API

Jun 2021 – Jul 2021

Private Project

- Simple loan management REST API made with Flask and SQLite.
- Token-based authentication.
- Flask Blueprints for future scaling.

PCOcare: PCOS Detection & Prediction using ML ☑

Oct 2020 - Nov 2020

Research Project

- Utilised Exploratory Data Analysis to build a hypothesis.
- Feature Engineering, Model building, and Ensembling of models were used to test the hypothesis.

CERTIFICATES

- TensorFlow: Advanced Techniques ☑
- Docker and Kubernetes: The Complete Guide
- Modern Application Development with Python on AWS